Michelle Norton

679 S. Reed Ct #2-407, Lakewood, CO 80226 | 303.847.6204 | tirjasdyn@gmail.com | MICHELLEJNORTON.COM

SUMMARY

Web developer with core competencies in advanced principles of web page layout, web site architecture, database integration, and web standards. Sophisticated web site development using scripting languages; web programming and database management knowledge combines with well-honed problem solving strengths to meet the challenges of client needs and technical innovation. Enjoy coding and writing concise documentation that fully details software development lifecycles, editing and site maintenance. Five years of experience in customer service, technical support and web design. *Qualifications include*:

Web Software, Scripting and Database: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, MySQL, SQL Server, Balsamiq,

Content Management Systems (CMS), WordPress

Digital Marketing: SEO, Social Media, Content Writing

Adobe Suite: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver, MS Office Suite.

Design: Responsive, Mobile, Parallax

EDUCATION

Multimedia Design and Development with a specialization in Web Design and Development

DeVry University, Colorado

degree earned in October 2015

- Acquired skills in programming logic and life cycles, emerging media, audio/video editing and
- Created and distributed web-enabled and other digital media.
- Built, created, and maintained websites and digital projects. Student portfolio: http://mnorton6.mydevryportfolio.com/portfolio/

Bachelor of Arts in English: Creative Writing

portfolio.

Colorado State University, 2002

WEB DEVELOPMENT & DESIGN EXPERIENCE

Web Designer - Robert ELoup Jewish Community Center

2008 - 2010

Web Design & maintenance for jccdenger.org & macc.org. Eblasts, microsite development, community calendars, event sites, logo design, movie trailer editing.

Web Designer / Receptionist - JB Olsen Construction

2006 - 2008

Redesign of jbolsen.org. WordPress support and maintenance. Design of magazine ads, sell sheets, project books. Worked a 16 line phone reception.

WORK HISTORY

Customer Service Rep (PL Claims) | In house App Development (Claim Helper) - Safeco 2014 – PRESENT In bound calls for personal claims, auto and property. Note taking web app, utilizing JavaScript & JQuery.

Sales Agent/ Retention Plan Specialist/ Chat Agent - Connextions

2012 and 2013 - 2014

Accomplished a high volume of sales calls for in bound calls center sales environment for United Health Care Medicare & Kaiser Permanente. Retention Sales for Kaiser Permanente. Chat Customer Sales Service for Kaiser Permanente.

TSR (Dispatch) - Manpower for IBM

2013

Administered calls for nationwide dispatch to schedule service techs to IBM sever customers.

Health Outreach Specialist - Apple One for WellPoint, Anthem Blue Cross & Blue Shield

2012

Completed outbound calls to customers to assist with enrollment for health insurance wellness programs.

Customer Care Representative - Alpine Access for XBox

2011

Took in-bound calls for billing and technical support for XBOX 360.